Finding Aid for James B. Griffin Papers 1922-1997
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Travel and International Initiatives, 1946-1973
  The Travel and International Initiatives series, 1946-1973 (1 linear foot), contains correspondence, planning materials, proposals and reports related to international travel and archaeological exchange programs in which Griffin was involved. These include a six-month stint in Mexico in 1946, a year-long European study tour from 1953 to 1954, study in the former Soviet Union in 1962, and University of Michigan cooperative agreements for archaeological digs in Poland, the former Yugoslavia, and Israel. (Please note that most of the general correspondence Griffin sent or received while traveling is filed in the Correspondence, 1930-1975 series. In particular, Griffin's correspondence to and from the Museum of Anthropology during his European study tour is filed under "Griffin, James B.")
  - Mexico, 1945-1946 (Box 65)
  - Michigan Expedition to the Aleutians, 1948 (Box 65)
  - Cuba, 1953 (Box 65)
  - Europe, 1953-1954
    - Notebook (includes research and logistical notes), 1953-1954 (Box 65)
  - Japan, 1956-1957 (Box 66)
  - Soviet Union, 1958-1962; 2 folders (Box 66)
  - Denmark, 1963 (Box 66)
  - Turkey, 1963 (Box 66)
  - Europe, 1969 (Box 66)
  - Israel
    - 1966-1969, 2 folders (Box 66)
    - 1973 (Box 66)
  - Po, 1964-1970; 2 folders (Box 66)
  - Yugoslavia
    - 1966-1969 (Box 66)
    - 1969-1971 (Box 66)
    - 1971-1973 (Box 66)
  - India, 1970-1972 (Box 66)
- Writings and Publications, 1930-1997
  The Writings and Publications series, 1930-1997 (14 linear feet), contains drafts, final versions, and supporting information for articles, books, conference papers, reports, reviews and other writing by Griffin and others. The series is divided into two subseries, By Griffin and By Others.
  - By Griffin
    Most of the works in the By Griffin subseries are arranged in individual folders by the title of the work then sorted chronologically. These folders often contain multiple drafts, supporting research, and correspondence regarding the publication of the work. Occasionally photographs or other visual materials are also included. Most of the works in this subseries were eventually published, though virtually all of the material included here is in its pre-publication form. Of particular note are drafts and background research for Griffin's M.A. and Ph.D. theses and his first book The Fort Ancient Aspect, reports from Griffin's work with the Ceramic Repository of the Eastern United States, and supplementary material for biographical essays on various archaeologists, including Carl Guthe. Book reviews, information related to Academic Press' New World Archaeological Record monograph series, for which Griffin served as editor, and a small amount of miscellaneous material are included at the end of the subseries.
    - "Aboriginal Mortuary Customs in the Western Half of the Northeast Woodlands Area" (master's thesis), [1930] (Box 66)
    - "The Tioga Point Museum Expedition for 1931,", circa 1931 (Box 66)
    - "Report Upon Sherds from the Fox Farm Site, Mason County, Kentucky,", circa 1933 (Box 66)
    - "An Analysis of the Fort Ancient Culture,", 1935 (Box 66)
    - "The Cultural Significance of the Ceramic Remains from the Norris Basin" (Ph.D. dissertation), [1936]
      - Manuscript (Box 66)
      - Negatives of Charts (Box 66)
    - "A Report on the Ceramics of Wheeler Basin," [1936]
      - Report (Box 67)
      - Drafts (Box 67)
    - "The Relation Between Archaeology and Ethnology in the United States,", 1930s (Box 67)
    - "Contributions to the Archaeology of the Illinois River Valley,", 1941 (Box 67)
    - "Additional Hopewell Material from Illinois,", 1941-1942 (Box 67)
    - "Comments on the Pottery of the Huff Focus (Mandan),", 1942 (Box 67)
    - The Fort Ancient Aspect
      - Background Research (Box 67)
      - Draft, 1942; 2 folders (Box 67)
      - Maps (Box 67)
      - Plates and Drawings, 2 folders; 1 folders (Box 67)
      - Reviews, 1944; 2 folders (Box 68)
    - "Painted Pottery Figurines from Illinois" (with W.C. McKern and P.F. Titterington), 1943 (Box 68)
    - "The Box Elder Mound in La Salle County, Illinois,", 1944 (Box 68)
    - "Cultural Change and Continuity in Eastern United States Archaeology,", 1941-1946 (Box 68)
    - "Some Pottery Types of the Late Nahua Occupation of the Valley of Mexico" (with Antonieta Espejo), 1946 (Box 68)
    - "Notes on Some Ceramic Techniques and Intrusions in Central Mexico,", 1944-1947 (Box 68)
    - "The Cahokia Ceramic Complexes,", 1947 (Box 68)
    - "How We Study Early Cultures" (for The Book of Science), 1947 (Box 68)
    - Foreword and Supplementary Material for A Study of the Glacial Kame Culture of Michigan, Ohio and Indiana (by W. Cunningham), 1943-1948; 2 folders (Box 68)
    - "The Late Prehistoric Cultures of the Ohio Valley,", 1951 (Box 68)
    - "Prehistoric Chronology Estimates in the Eastern United States and Central Mexico, 1940-1950,", 1951 (Box 68)
    - "A Preliminary Statement on the Collection from the Grassy Lake Site (Ms 4) Madison County, Illinois," [1951] (Box 68)
    - "An Analysis of Early and Middle Woodland Pottery in the Illinois Area," [1952] (Box 68)
    - "An Interpretation of the Place of Spiro in Southeastern Archaeology," [1952] (Box 68)
    - "A Preview of the Ceramic Relationships of the Snyders Site, Calhoun County, Illinois,", 1952 (Box 68)
    - "Prehistoric Cultures of the Central Mississippi Valley," [1952] (Box 68)
    - "Radiocarbon Dates for the Eastern United States," [1952] (Box 68)
    - Programa de Historia de Amrica, 1952-1953; 2 folders (Box 68)
    - Archaeology of Eastern United States Reviews, 1953 (Box 68)
    - "Comments on the Cultural Position of the Bintz Site, Campbell County, Kentucky," [1953] (Box 68)
    - "Introduction to the Indian History of the United States and Canada" (for Programa de Historia de Amrica), 1953 (Box 68)
    - "Chronology and Dating Processes" (for Yearbook of Anthropology), 1954 (Box 68)
    - "Observations on the Grooved Axe in North America,", 1955 (Box 68)
    - "Prehistoric Settlement Patterns in the Northern Mississippi Valley and the Upper Great Lakes,", 1955 (Box 68)
    - "Science Museums at the University of Michigan,", 1955 (Box 68)
    - "Notes on the Prehistory of the Upper Great Lakes Area" (with Emerson Greenman and Albert Spaulding), 1956 (Box 68)
    - "Reliability of Radiocarbon Dates for Late Glacial and Recent Times in Central and Eastern North America,", 1956 (Box 68)
    - "A Brief Review of the Pursuit of Archaeology in the United States,", 1958 (Box 68)
    - "An Interpretation of Asiatic Contributions to the Prehistoric Culture of Eastern North America,", 1958 (Box 68)
    - "An Hypothesis for the Prehistory of the Winnebago" (and Paul Radin festschrift), 1958-1960 (Box 69)
    - "An Interpretation of Asiatic Contributions to the Prehistoric Culture of Eastern North America,", 1960 (Box 69)
    - "North America" (for Encyclopaedia Britannica), 1960 (Box 69)
    - "Some Prehistoric Connections Between Siberia and Eastern North America,", circa 1960 (Box 69)
    - "Mesoamerica and the Eastern United States in Prehistoric Times" (for Handbook of Middle American Indians), 1959-1961 (Box 69)
    - "Post-Glacial Ecology and Culture Changes in the Great Lakes Area of North America,", 1960-1961 (Box 69)
    - "Commentary on 'Neolithic Diffusion Rates'" (by M. Edmonson), [1961] (Box 69)
    - "Relationships Between the Caddoan Area and the Mississippi Valley,", 1961 (Box 69)
    - "The Short-Nosed God from the Emmons Site, Illinois" (with Dan F. Morse), 1961 (Box 69)
    - "The Origins of Prehistoric North American Pottery" (for IUPPS-Rome), 1962 (Box 69)
    - "A Summary of New World Prehistory,", 1962-1964 (Box 69)
    - "The Ceramic Complexes at Iyatayet" (for The Archaeology of Cape Denbigh by J.L. Giddings), [1964] (Box 69)
    - "A Non-Neolithic Copper Industry in North America," (includes photos), 1964 (Box 69)
    - "Late Quaternary Prehistory in the Northeastern Woodlands" (for The Quaternary of the United States), 1963-1965 (Box 69)
    - "The Calumet Ancient Pit,", 1965 (Box 69)
    - "Climatic Change in American Prehistory,", 1965 (Box 69)
    - "Hopewell and the Dark Black Glass,", 1965 (Box 69)
    - "Mesoamerica and the Eastern United States in Prehistoric Times" (in Handbook of Middle American Indians), 1965 (Box 69)
    - "Eastern North American Archaeology: A Summary"
      - General, 1964-1967 (Box 69)
      - Photos and Plates, 1964-1967 (Box 69)
    - "Northeast Asian and Northwestern American Ceramics,", 1966 (Box 69)
    - Encyclopaedia Britannica-- Miscellaneous, 1967 (Box 69)
    - "Observation on Illinois Prehistory in Late Pleistocene and Early Recent Times,", 1967-1968 (Box 69)
    - "Indian, North American: Prehistory" (for Encyclopaedia Britannica), 1969 (Box 69)
    - Foreword to Hiwassee Island (by Lewis and Kneberg), 1969-1970 (Box 69)
    - The Burial Complexes of the Knight and Norton Mounds in Illinois and Michigan (with Flanders and Titterington), [1970] (2 of 3 folders) (Box 69)
    - The Burial Complexes of the Knight and Norton Mounds in Illinois and Michigan (with Flanders and Titterington), [1970] (3 of 3 folders) (Box 70)
    - "The Study of Early Cultures,", 1970 (Box 70)
    - "New World Archaeology" (for Science Year), 1969-1971 (Box 70)
    - Introduction to Reissue of Ancient Monuments of the Mississippi Valley (by E.G. Squier and E.H. Davis), 1971 (Box 70)
    - "Site Surveys" (for Addison-Wesley Modular Publications), 1970-1972 (Box 70)
    - Review of Archaeological Survey in the Lower Yazoo Basin, Mississippi, 1949-1955 (by Philip Phillips), 1972 (Box 70)
    - Foreword to The Adena People (by Webb and Snow), 1974 (Box 70)
    - "New World Archaeology" (for Science Year), 1972-1975 (Box 70)
    - "Adena" (for Encyclopedia of Indians of the Americas), 1973-1975 (Box 70)
    - "A Commentary on Certain Opinions About Mississippian Cultural Complexes,", 1975 (Box 70)
    - "A Commentary on Some Archaeological Activities in the Mid-Continent, 1925-1975," (Box 70)
    - "Southeast and its External Relations" (for Handbook of North American Indians), 1971-1976 (Box 70)
    - Carl Guthe Obituary (includes photos), 1974-1976 (Box 70)
    - "The University of Michigan Excavations at the Pulcher Site in 1950" (and Albert Spaulding festschrift), 1975-1976 (Box 70)
    - "A Brief Tribute to David L. DeJarnette,", 1976 (Box 70)
    - "Some Suggested Alterations of Certain Portions of 'An Anthropological Perspective,'", 1976 (Box 70)
    - "The 'Turtle Egg' Site (20-GS-26), Genesee County, Michigan," (the Budd site), 1976 (Box 70)
    - "An Appreciation of Irving Benjamin Rouse" (and Rouse festschrift), 1972-1977 (Box 70)
    - "Late Woodland Ramblings,", 1977 (Box 70)
    - Obituary for T.M.N. Lewis, 1977 (Box 70)
    - "Volney H. Jones Ethnobotanist" (and Jones festschrift), 1977 (Box 70)
    - Foreword to Mississippian Settlement Patterns, 1978 (Box 70)
    - "Late Prehistory of the Ohio Valley" (for Handbook of North American Indians), 1968-1979; 2 folders (Box 70)
    - "Eastern United States" (for Chronologies in New World Archaeology), 1971-1979 (Box 71)
    - "The Midlands and the Northeastern United States" (for Ancient Native Americans), 1976-1979; 2 folders (Box 71)
    - "New World Archaeology" (for Science Year), (includes photos), 1976-1979 (Box 71)
    - Academic American Encyclopedia, 1977-1979 (Box 71)
    - "A Commentary on 'Storm Over Ungava,'" (includes photos), 1979 (Box 71)
    - "Agricultural Groups in North America" (for Cambridge Encyclopedia of Archaeology), 1978-1980 (Box 71)
    - "The Prehistoric Southeast and Middle America: A 1980 Interpretation," 1980 (Box 71)
    - "The Acquisition of a Little Known Pottery Haul from the Lower Mississippi Valley,", 1981 (Box 71)
    - "Changing Concepts of the Prehistoric Mississippian Cultures of the Eastern United States,", 1981 (Box 71)
    - "The Midlands" (for Ancient North Americans), 1979-1982 (Box 71)
    - "William H. Sears, Southeastern Archaeologist: A Tribute,", 1982 (Box 71)
    - "George Irving Quimby: The Formative Years" (and Quimby festschrift), 1980-1983 (Box 71)
    - "Joffre Lanning Coe: The Quiet Giant of Southeastern Archaeology" (and Coe festschrift), 1980-1983; 2 folders (Box 71)
    - The Snyders Mounds and Five Other Mound Groups in Calhoun County, Illinois, 1980-1983; 2 folders (Box 71)
    - "Observations on the FAI-270 Project" (for American Bottom Archaeology), 1982-1984 (Box 71)
    - Comments from the Tchula Conference (for proceedings), 1983-1984 (Box 71)
    - Review of Pre-Columbian Shell Engravings from the Craig Mound at Spiro, Oklahoma (by Philip Phillips and James A. Brown), 1984 (Box 71)
    - "The Formation of the Society for American Archaeology,", 1984-1985 (Box 71)
    - "An Individual's Participation in American Archaeology, 1928-1985" (for Annual Review of Anthropology), 1984-1985 (Box 71)
    - "A Mammoth Fraud in Science" (with David J. Meltzer, Bruce D. Smith and William C. Sturtevant), 1988 (Box 71)
    - Paper on Ohio Hopewell for Anthropological Society of Washington, 1990 (Box 72)
    - "A Prehistoric Cultural Climax in the Midwest: Ohio Hopewell,", 1991 (Box 72)
    - "Havana Beginnings 1930-50" (foreword to The Sister Creeks Site), 1991-1992 (Box 72)
    - "Women in Archaeology: A Point of Clarification,", 1992 (Box 72)
    - "Dawn of Colonization, a.d. 1400-1700,", 1993 (Box 72)
    - "Interpretations of Ohio Hopewell 1845-1984 and the Recent Emphasis on the Study of Dispersed Hamlets" (for Ohio Hopewell Community Organization), 1994-1996, 2 folders (Box 72)
    - Biographical Essay on James A. Ford, undated (Box 72)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Book Reviews
        - 1945-1978, 3 folders (Box 72)
        - 1989-1992 (Box 72)
      - Introduction to Archaeology (proposed textbook), 1959 (Box 72)
      - Mailing Lists for Selected Publications (Box 72)
      - Miscellaneous Royalty and Reprint Information, 1979-1996 (Box 72)
      - North American Archaeologist (editorial board), 1977-1978 (Box 72)
      - North American Archaeology (proposed textbook), 1963-1964 (Box 72)
      - Ohio's Natural Heritage (advisory committee), 1977-1978 (Box 72)
      - Reader's Digest (consulting), 1983-1984 (Box 72)
      - Reprints, 1950-1985; 2 folders (Box 72)
      - Soviet Anthropology and Archaeology (advisory committee), 1962 (Box 72)
      - Time-Life Books (consulting), 1992 (Box 72)
      - Unpublished Papers and Talks, 1941-1983 (Box 72)
      - New World Archaeological Record (series editor)
        - Academic Press
          - 1972-1983 (Box 72)
          - 1984-1993, 2 folders (Box 72)
          - Stanley Holwitz, 1971-1978 (Box 73)
        - Authors, 1972-1982; 5 folders (Box 73)
  - By Others
    The By Others subseries is arranged alphabetically by the author's name. The subseries contains unpublished reports, conference papers, and drafts (which may or may not have later been published); published articles, reprints and published site reports sent to Griffin as a courtesy have been removed. Some individual titles are listed, but when an author's name is followed by a folder titled "Papers," this indicates that the folder contains multiple writings that were filed collectively by Griffin under the author's name rather than by title. Griffin served as a formal or informal advisor to the authors of many of the works in this subseries. Some works include Griffin's comments and criticisms.
    - Addington, James E.
      - "Interrelationship of Diet and Dental Condition in Ohio Hopewell,", 1976 (Box 73)
    - Apfelstadt, Gary A. and Gilbert C.
      - "Middle Woodland in Southwestern Indiana: Notes on the Kuester Site Area and Assemblage,", undated (Box 73)
    - Asch, David L. and Nancy B.
      - Papers, 1971-1980 (Box 73)
    - Baker, Frank Collins
      - "A Study in Ethnozoology of the Prehistoric Indians of Illinois,", undated (Box 73)
    - Bartoletti, Mario D.
      - "The Heying Site, Missouri,", 1965 (Box 73)
    - Bastian, Tyler
      - "Trace Element and Metallographic Studies of Prehistoric Copper Artifacts in North America: A Review,", 1961 (Box 73)
    - Beaubien, Paul L.
      - "Cultural Variation Within Two Woodland Mound Groups of Northeastern Iowa,", 1953 (Box 73)
    - Belmont, John S.
      - "Painted Pottery Horizons in the Southern Mississippi Valley" (with Stephen Williams), 1979 (Box 73)
      - "A Reconnaissance of the Boeuf Basin, Louisiana,", 1981 (Box 73)
    - Bender, Margaret A.
      - "Further Light on Carbon Isotopes and Hopewell Architecture" (with David A. Baerreis and Raymond Steventon), 1979 (Box 73)
    - Benn, David W.
      - "The Woodland Ceramic Sequence in the Culture History of Northeast Iowa,", 1976 (Box 73)
    - Bennett, John W.
      - Papers, 1943-1945 (Box 73)
    - Bentzen, Raymond C.
      - "Preliminary Report on the Little Bald Mountain Site,", 1957 (Box 73)
    - Black, Thomas K., III
      - "The Biological and Social Analysis of a Mississippian Cemetery from Southeast Missouri: The Turner Site, 23BU21A," (prelim paper), 1974; 2 folders (Box 73)
    - Boos, Frank
      - "An Analysis of an Urn of a Mixtec Old-Man God,", 1962 (Box 73)
    - Bowen, Jonathan E.
      - "The Sandusky River Area of North-Central Ohio: 1300-1600,", 1994 (Box 73)
    - Brace, C. Loring
      - Papers, undated (Box 73)
    - Braun, David
      - Papers, 1975-1981 (Box 73)
    - Brennan, Louis
      - "The Twombly Landing Site,", 1967 (Box 73)
    - Brown, Ian
      - "Archaeology of the Natchez Bluffs Region, Mississippi: Hypothesized Cultural and Environmental Factors Influencing Local Population Movements" (with Jeffrey Brain), 1976 (Box 73)
      - "Fort St. Pierre and Associated French and Indian Sites in the Yazoo Bluffs Region: Mississippi: A Report on the Investigations," 1977", 1976 (Box 73)
      - Papers, 1978-1995; 4 folders (Box 74)
    - Brown, James A.
      - "Spiro Art and Its Mortuary Contexts,", 1973 (Box 74)
        (includes notes by Griffin for a talk on the subject)
      - "The Prairie Peninsula as an Aboriginal Area of Cultural Interaction in the Midwest,", 1965 (Box 74)
      - Papers, 1966-1995 (Box 74)
    - Broyles, Bettye J.
      - "Bibliography of Pottery Types,", 1965-1966 (Box 74)
    - Bryan, Alan L.
      - "The Significance of Fluted Points in Alaska to Early American Prehistory,", 1967 (Box 74)
        (includes "A Technological Description of Artifacts in Assemblage I, Wilson Butte Cave, Idaho," undated)
    - Bryson, Reid
      - Papers on Climatology, 1966-1996; 2 folders (Box 74)
    - Bush, Deborah A.
      - "A Ceramic Analysis of the Buckmyer Site,", 1974 (Box 74)
    - Butterfield, Ira W.
      - "Reconnaissance Near the Mouth of Fortyeight Creek, Wayne County, Tennessee,", 1959 (Box 74)
    - Caldwell, Joseph R.
      - "Progress Report on Excavation at Tugalo (9 St 1 -- Georgia),", 1957 (Box 74)
    - Carbone, Victor A.
      - "Environment and Society in Archaic and Woodland Times,", undated (Box 74)
    - Carneiro, Robert L.
      - "Slash-and-Burn Agriculture: A Closer Look at Its Implications for Settlement Pattern,", 1956 (Box 74)
    - Charles, Douglas K.
      - "Subsistence Settlement in West Central Illinois: Contributions from the Archaeology of Mortuary Sites," (includes photos), 1980-1982 (Box 74)
    - Clark, Jerry E.
      - "Fort Ancient Social Organization and Ethnic Identification: A Lexico-Reconstruction,", 1972-1973 (Box 74)
    - Cleland, Charles E.
      - "Analysis of the Animal Remains in the Prehistoric Ozark Bluff-Dwellings of Northwest Arkansas, 1960 (Box 74)
      - Papers, undated; 1964-1965 (Box 74)
    - Connaway, John
      - "The Bonds Village Site 22 Tu 530: A Preliminary Report on Archaeological Investigations at a Woodland Village Site in Tunica County, Mississippi,", 1968 (Box 74)
    - Cowgill, George L.
      - Papers, 1965-1966 (Box 74)
    - Dalbey, Timothy S.
      - "Salvage Logistics at the Dupont Site (33HA11),", 1976 (Box 74)
    - Delavan, Wayne
      - "A Study of the E.U. Woods Lodge Site Collection, 1950 (Box 74)
    - Denny, J. Peter
      - "The Algonquian Migration from the Columbia Plateau to the Midwest, Circa 1600 B.C.: Correlating Linguistics and Archaeology,", 1991 (Box 74)
    - DeRousseau, C. Jean
      - "Mortuary Site Survey and Paleodemography in the Lower Illinois River Valley,", 1975 (Box 74)
    - Dixon, Keith A.
      - Papers, 1962-1966 (Box 74)
    - Doran, Glen H. and Dickel, David N.
      - Papers Related to the Windover Site, Florida, 1986-1987 (Box 74)
    - Douglas, John G.
      - "Salvage Archaeology in the Middle Fork Reservoir: Excavations at the Collins Site,", 1970 (Box 74)
      - "Salvage Archaeology in the Middle Fork Reservoir: Excavations at the Collins Site and Indian Springs Mound, 1971-1972,", 1973 (Box 74)
    - Drooker, Penelope
      - Papers, 1994 (Box 74)
    - Dunn, Mary Eubanks
      - "Phytolith Analysis in Archaeology: How Useful a Tool?,", 1981 (Box 74)
    - Eggan, Fred R.
      - "The Archaeology of Will County," [1933] (Box 74)
    - Embree, Lester E.
      - "The New Philosophy of Science and the New Archaeology: Proposal for 'A Study of the New Archaeology,'", 1979 (Box 74)
    - Emerson, Thomas E. and Hughes, Randall E.
      - "Preliminary Sourcing of Cahokia Middle Mississippian Flint Clay Figurines,", 1995 (Box 74)
    - Esarey, Duane
      - Papers, 1990-1993 (Box 74)
    - Eyman, Charles E.
      - Papers, 1967 (Box 74)
    - Fairbanks, Charles H.
      - "A Preliminary Segregation of Etowah, Savannah, and Lamar,", 1950 (Box 74)
    - Farnsworth, Kenneth B.
      - Papers, 1971-1973 (Box 74)
    - Farrand, William R.
      - "Evidence of Ancient Levels of Lake Superior in the Huron Mountains Area,", 1960 (Box 75)
      - Papers, 1966-1969 (Box 75)
    - Faulkner, Charles H.
      - "Plant Food Remains on Tennessee Sites: A Preliminary Report," (with J.B. Graham), 1965 (Box 75)
      - Papers, 1971-1974 (Box 75)
    - Ferguson, Henry G.
      - Preface to Moyaone by Alice L.L. Ferguson, 1957 (Box 75)
    - Fitting, James E.
      - Papers, 1965-1971; 3 folders (Box 75)
    - Flannery, Kent V.
      - "Prehistory and Human Ecology of the Puna de Junin: A Preliminary Report on the University of San Marcos' Collaboration with U.S. Universities during 1972-73" (edited with Ramiro Matos Mendieta), 1974 (Box 75)
    - Fogel, Ira
      - "The Dispersal of Copper Artifacts in the Late Archaic Period of Prehistoric North America,", 1966 (Box 75)
    - Ford, James A.
      - "An Examination of Some Theories and Methods of Ceramic Analysis,", 1938 (Box 75)
        (M.A. thesis)
    - Ford, Richard I.
      - Papers, 1965-1980 (Box 75)
    - Fowler, Melvin L.
      - "The Origin of Plant Cultivation in the Central Mississippi Valley: A Hypothesis,", 1957 (Box 75)
    - Frison, George C.
      - "A Functional Analysis of Certain Chipped Stone Tools,", 1967 (Box 75)
    - Gardner, William M.
      - Papers Regarding the Thunderbird Site, 1972-1974 (Box 75)
    - Garland, Elizabeth Baldwin
      - "Hacklander Site: Report on 1975 Excavations," 1976 (Box 75)
    - Gibson, Jon L.
      - Hopewell Papers (with Griffin's comments), 1969-1974 (Box 75)
    - Giddings, J.L.
      - "Some Arctic Spear Points and Their Counterparts,", undated (Box 75)
    - Goggin, John M.
      - "An Introductory Course of Timucua Archaeology,", 1952 (Box 75)
    - Gorski, Linda
      - "An Annotated Bibliography of Oneota Culture,", 1977 (Box 75)
    - Green, William
      - "The Middle Mississippian Presence in the Upper Mississippi Valley: The Evidence from Trempealeau, Wisconsin,", 1984 (Box 75)
    - Griffin, John W.
      - ""Upper Mississippi at the Fisher Site,", 1948 (Box 75)
    - Hall, Robert L.